☆独家制作☆
喜马拉雅主播 & 微信公众号:
美国青少年英语
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[OMINOUS SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[RADIO STATIC CRACKLING]
- Still nothing? - Nothing.
-还是没有回应吗  -没有
Food court? You sure they said food court?
食物法庭  你确定他们说食物法庭
I'm sorry, have my translation skills been letting you down?
抱歉  是不是我的翻译水平让你失望了
We don't know it's your kids.
我们不清楚是不是你的孩子
Yes, we do.
不  我们清楚
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[ENGINE REVVING]
[SCREAMING AND SOBBING]
[ELEVEN WAILS IN PAIN]
[FLESH SIZZLING]
- What is that? - [MIKE] There's something in there.
-那是什么  -有东西在里面
- [ELEVEN] No! - Jesus Christ.
-不  -老天爷
Keep her talking. Keep her awake, okay?
跟她说话  让她保持清醒  好吗
[DUSTIN] Jesus Christ.
老天爷
[GRUNTS]
[PANTING]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Hey, hey, hey. Stay awake, stay awake.
坚持住  坚持住
Let's get her on this side, on this side.
把她挪到这边  这边
- Easy, easy, easy, easy. - [ROBIN] It's, uh...
-放松  放松  -这...
You know, it's not actually that bad. There was a...
其实还没那么糟  有个...
The goalie on my soccer team, Beth Wildfire,
我足球队的守门员  贝丝·威尔德菲尔
this other girl slid into her leg, and the bone came out of her knee,
另外一个球员撞到了她的腿上 骨头都从膝盖支出来了
- six inches or something, it was insane. - Robin.
-大概有六英寸长  太可怕了  -罗宾
- Yeah? - You're not helping.
-什么  -你是在帮倒忙
- I'm sorry. - [RUNNING FOOTSTEPS]
抱歉
Okay. All right, El?
还好吗  一一
This is gonna hurt like hell, okay?
这会非常疼的
- [SOBS] Okay. - [JONATHAN] Need you to stay real still.
-好的  -我要你保持完全不动
Here, you're gonna want to bite down on this, okay?
拿着  咬着这个  好吗
[DUSTIN] Jesus Christ.
老天爷
[ELEVEN WHIMPERS]
[DUSTIN] Holy shit. Holy shit.
我的天
Do it.
来吧
Okay.
好
[DUSTIN MURMURS UNCOMFORTABLY]
[ELEVEN SCREAMS]
[SCREAMING CONTINUES]
[NANCY EXCLAIMS]
[DUSTIN] Oh, shit.
该死
[SCREAMS, SOBS]
- [ELEVEN SCREECHES IN PAIN] - [MIKE EXCLAIMS]
[ELEVEN WHIMPERS]
[SCREAMS]
- Jonathan! - Stop talking!
-乔纳森  -别说话
[SCREAMS]
- Goddamn it! - No! Stop it!
-该死  -不  住手
Stop! Stop!
停  停
[GRUNTS] I can do it.
我自己来
I can do it.
[ELEVEN PANTING]
[LOW FREQUENCY VIBRATION]
[ELEVEN WAILS]
[ELEVEN] God!
天呐
- [VIBRATIONS INTENSIFY] - [ELEVEN] God!
[CREATURE CHITTERING]
[WAILS]
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMING CONTINUES]
- [MAX YELPS] - [ELEVEN'S SCREAMING CONTINUES]
[CREATURE SHRIEKS]
[SCREAM CONTINUES]
[GRUNTS]
[CREATURE CHITTERS PAINFULLY]
[SCREECHING]
[INTENSE SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
怪奇物语  第三季
第八集  星庭之战
星庭商场
[MIKE] The Mind Flayer, it built this monster in Hawkins,
吸灵魔  它在霍金斯造了这个怪物
to stop El, to kill her and pave a way into our world.
来阻止一一 杀了她便能入侵我们的世界
[NANCY] And it almost did. That was just one tiny piece of it.
它差点就得手了  这只是它的一小部分
[HOPPER] How big is this thing?
这个怪物有多大
[JONATHAN] It's big. [MURMURS]
很大
- Thirty feet, at least. - [LUCAS] Yeah.
-至少两米高  -是的
It sorta destroyed your cabin.
它摧毁了你的小屋
Sorry.
抱歉
Okay, so, just to be clear, this...
我确认一下  这头
this big fleshy spider thing that hurt El,
这头弄伤一一的大肉球蜘蛛
it's some kind of gigantic... weapon?
是某种巨型武器吗
- Yes. - But instead of, like, screws and metal,
-是的  -但并不是用螺钉和金属打造的
the Mind Flayer made its weapon...
吸灵魔是用融化的人体
with melted people.
打造它的武器
- Yes, exactly. - [STEVE] Yeah, okay.
-没错  -好吧
I... Yeah, I'm just making sure.
我只是想再确认一下
Are we sure this thing is still out there, still alive?
这头怪物真的还在外面  还活着吗
El beat the shit out of it, but, yeah, it's still alive.
一一暴揍了它一顿  但它的确还活着
But if we close the gate again...
但如果我们再将入口关闭
We cut the brain off from the body.
我们就能将大脑控制切断
And kill it.
就能杀了它
Theoretically.
理论上是这样
[MURRAY] Yoo-hoo!
[PAPERS RUSTLING]
Yoo-hoo!
Okay, this is what Alexei called "the hub".
这就是阿列克西所谓的"枢纽"
Now, the hub takes us to the vault room.
这个枢纽是能通向保险库的
Okay, where's the gate?
入口在哪
Right here. I don't know the scale on this,
就在这  我不知道图上的比例是多少
but I think it's fairly close to the vault room,
但我觉得应该离保险库非常近
maybe 50 feet or so.
大概有个50英尺
More like 500.
500英尺还差不多
What, you're just gonna waltz in there like
怎么  你还想在里面跳上一段华尔兹吗
it's commie Disneyland or something?
你以为那是共产主义迪斯尼乐园吗
I'm sorry, who are you?
抱歉  你是谁
Erica Sinclair. Who are you?
艾瑞卡·辛克莱  你又是谁
Murray...
莫里
Bauman.
鲍曼
Listen, Mr. Bunman,
听好了  鲍曼先生
I'm not trying to tell you how to do things,
我不是想对你指手画脚
but I've been down in that shithole for 24 hours.
但我曾在那鬼地方待过一天
And with all due respect, you do what this man tells you,
恕我直言  如果你们照他说的做
you're all gonna die.
你们都会死
I'm sorry, why is this four-year-old speaking to me?
抱歉 这个四岁的小屁孩有什么资格跟我说话
Um, I'm ten, you bald bastard!
我十岁了  你个秃头混蛋
- Erica! - Just the facts!
-艾瑞卡  -这就是事实
She's right. You're all gonna die, but you don't have to. Excuse me.
他说得对  你们都会死的 但这可以避免
- Sorry, may I? - Please.
-抱歉  我能看看吗  -请
Okay, see this room here? This is a storage facility.
看到这个房间了吗  这是贮藏库
There's a hatch in here
这有个小舱口
that feeds into their underground ventilation system.
能进入他们的地下通风系统
That will lead you to the base of the weapon.
这能通向他们的武器库
It's a bit of a maze down there,
这下面就像迷宫一样
but between me and Erica, we can show you the way.
但有我和艾瑞卡  我们能给你们带路
You can show us the way?
你们能给我们带路
Don't worry, you can do all the fighting
别担心  你们尽管去当英雄
and the dangerous hero shit,
和那些危险的东西作战
and we'll just be your...
我们只是你们的
navigators.
导航员
No.
不行
Nope.
[COCKS ASSAULT RIFLE]
[ERICA] Well, that settles it.
那就这样了
He's gonna die. They're gonna die.
他死定了  他们都死定了
Yep, most likely.
是的  非常有可能
You guys survived.
你们就逃出来了
Barely.
差点不辞那个了
We could've really used you guys down there.
我们在下面很需要你们
Could've used you up here, too.
我们这里也很需要你
Yeah, man. We missed you, dude.
是啊  我们很想你  伙计
Yeah. Big-time.
是啊  非常想你
I missed you guys, too.
我也很想你们的
Big-time.
非常想念
Please don't cry, nerds.
可别哭了  书呆
- Erica. - Keep saying my name, see what happens.
-艾瑞卡  -你再叫我名字一遍试试
Hey, heads up. You can navigate, just from someplace safe.
接着  你可以导航  但必须是在安全的地方
- It's not that simple. - The signal won't reach.
这没那么简单 -信号没那么强  -这个不行
Not with this. You need something with a high enough frequency band
你得找一个高频率带的设备
to relay with the Russians' radio tower.
用苏联人的的无线电塔转接
But for that to work, you need someone
但那你得找一个
who has both seen their comms room
既见过他们通讯室
and has access to a super-powered handcrafted radio tower,
还有超强无线塔操作能力的家伙
one preferably already situated at the highest point in Hawkins.
这人最好还去过霍金斯的最高点
Oh, wait.
等等
That's me.
这不就是我吗
If you want us to navigate, you got us.
你想让我们来导航  没问题
But we need a head start.
但我们需要抢在前面
And a car.
还要一辆车
["GOLDRUSH" BY YELLO PLAYING]
Oh, man, now this...
天呐  这
this is what I'm talkin' about!
这才对嘛
- "Toddfather"? - [STEVE] Oh, screw Todd!
-"托德老爹"  -去他的托德吧
Steve's her daddy now.
现在史蒂夫才是她老爹
[ROBIN] Did you just talk about yourself in the third person?
你刚是用第三人称指代自己了吗
- Did he just call himself daddy? - All right, where are we going?
他刚刚是不是叫自己老爹了 好了  我们去哪
- Weathertop. - Weather-what?
-气象顶  -气象啥
- Just drive. - Okay. Jesus!
-快开吧  -知道了  老天
[ENGINE REVS]
托德老爹
[TIRES SQUEALING]
Bottom lock,
第一层的钥匙
second-to-top lock,
第二层的钥匙
third-to-top lock,
第三层的钥匙
top lock.
最高层的钥匙
Listen to me, I need to end this,
听我说  我得结束这一切
but I will be back before you know it, okay?
但是我马上就回来  好吗
- I don't know, Mom. - No, listen. You're gonna be safe there.
我不知道  妈 听着  你在那里会很安全
It's... It's far away from all this.
离这些都远远的
You just stick close to your brother and... and do whatever he says.
你只要待在哥哥身边 他说什么就做什么
No matter what. Okay?
不管怎么样  好吗
I'm not worried about me, Mom, I'm worried about you.
我担心的不是自己  妈  是你
Oh, honey, I'm gonna be fine.
宝贝  我会没事的
Okay? I'm gonna be fine.
我会平安无事的
[WILL WINCES]
Okay, Mom.
好了
Okay, Mom. That's enough.
知道了  妈  好了
- I'm gonna be fine. - Okay.
-我一定会没事的  -我相信你
Mom, I can't breathe.
妈  喘不上气了
- My battery's low, but... - [WILL] You're suffocating me.
-我精疲力尽了  但  -我要窒息了
... it will recharge.
会恢复的
I know it will, kid.
我知道它会  孩子
I know.
我知道
I can fight.
我能战斗
Better than any of us.
比我们中的任何人都强
But right now,
但是现在
I need you safe.
我只想让你安全
This thing is after you.
这个东西要的是你
It's not after me.
不是我
Do you understand?
你懂了吗
Hey...
I need you to understand.
我希望你能理解
[HOPPER, QUIETLY] Okay?
好吗
[MIKE] Hey.
We should probably go.
我们差不多该走了
[SIGHS]
[HOPPER MURMURS]
Mike?
迈克
Be careful.
注意安全
[SIGHS]
What?
怎么了
It's a two-man operation. Two!
这是双人行动  双人
- Yeah, well, change of plans. - Change of plans?
-对  但计划有变  -计划有变
Yeah. Will you explain it to him, please?
能拜托你给他解释解释吗
We have two options here, Jim.
我们有两个选择  吉姆
We can turn the machine off, or we can explode it.
关掉那个机器  或者炸了它
- Oh, yeah, says who? - Says the man who built it!
-是吗  谁说的  -造机器的人说的
- Yeah, and we wanna explode it! - Or else our heroic efforts
我们想炸掉它 不然我们这些英雄式的努力就白费了
will be for naught!
This is a three-man operation, Jim, not two.
这是三人行动  吉姆  不是双人
- Yeah, three. - [HOPPER GRUMBLES]
三人
[ELEVEN GRUNTS IN PAIN]
El, you're bleeding.
一一  你在流血
Are you okay?
你还好吗
Yeah.
还可以
- Here. - Okay.
到了
- [MIKE] Here. - [ELEVEN GROANS]
过来
- [MIKE] Lay down. - [ELEVEN WHIMPERS]
躺好
[ENGINE SPUTTERS]
- What's wrong? - I don't...
-有什么问题吗  -我不
I don't know.
我不知道
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
You can't be serious. Come on!
别开玩笑了  快点
Didn't your mom just buy this car?
这车不是你妈刚买的吗
Yes. I'm sure it's fine.
是啊  肯定没问题
- Did you leave the lights on? - No.
-你是不是忘关车灯了  -没有
- Do we have gas? - Yes!
-车有油吗  -有
[ENGINE SPUTTERS]
- Come on! - Whoa, whoa, whoa! Just stop, stop!
-加把劲吧  -住手  快住手
Pop the hood.
打开引擎盖
[HOOD LATCH CLUNKS]
- [JONATHAN] What the hell? - What?
-什么情况  -怎么了
[JONATHAN] The ignition cable's gone.
点火电缆不见了
[CAR ENGINE ROARING]
[ENGINE REVVING]
[OMINOUS SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[GASPS]
[REVVING CONTINUES]
Back in the mall!
回商场里去
快回去
- [NANCY] Go! Go, go, go! - [MIKE] Be careful!
快快快  小心点
- [NANCY] Go! Go! - [REVVING CONTINUES]
快走  快走
[NANCY AND JONATHAN] Go, go, go!
快快快
[REVVING CONTINUES]
[MURRAY] So then I yank those cables like I'm pulling weeds.
所以我像扯杂草一样把电缆拽出来
- And that'll set off the alarm... - According to Alexei,
警报会被触发 据阿列克西的说法是的
may his soul rest in peace.
希望他安息
Which should give you two an opening
你们两个就有机会
to retrieve the keys from the vault.
去地下室里拿钥匙
And then we just follow the map
然后我们跟着地图
to the observation room, turn the key...
去到观察室  转动钥匙
- Kaboom, we blow this sucker sky-high. - Yeah.
砰  我们把这个鬼地方炸上天
And then, once the rift is closed, we escape back through the vents.
等裂缝关闭了 我们从通风管道逃回去
Right under their commie noses.
就在他们这些共产党的眼皮底下
Then home free.
然后回家
Uh...
Oh, God, just because it wasn't your plan
老天  就算这不是你的方案
doesn't mean it was a bad plan.
也不意味着就是一个坏方案
I didn't say it was a bad plan.
我没说这是个坏方案
You made a noise.
你发出了不满的哼唧
- I did not make a noise. - You did too.
-我才没有哼唧  -你也哼唧了
I really think it's disrespectful...
我真心觉得这很不尊重人
What is up with you and noises?
你和哼唧声到底有什么过不去的
Children! Children!
孩子们  孩子们
It is a good plan.
这是个好方案
A solid B, which is laudable,
鉴于我们现在的情况和限制
given the situation and time constraints.
这个方案坚实可靠  值得赞扬
Dare I say, if it all goes right...
我敢说  如果一切顺利
[ELEVATOR THUDS TO A STOP]
... they'll never even know we were here.
他们甚至都不会知道我们来过
[IN RUSSIAN] Stop right there!
不许动
[IN RUSSIAN] Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
别开枪  别开枪
Documents, important documents...
文件  重要的文件
for the Lieutenant-Comrade!
要给中尉同志的
He called us, last minute.
他临时叫我们来
Pardon our sloppy appearance.
原谅我们事发突然过来了
[IN RUSSIAN] Lieutenant? What Lieutenant?
中尉  哪个中尉
Lieutenant...
中尉
Molotov?
莫洛托夫
[SOLDIERS MURMUR]
[SCREAMS]
[JOYCE WHIMPERS]
[PANTING]
Oh, shit.
我操
Jim...
吉姆
["HIGHER AND HIGHER" PLAYING]
This is crazy.
这太疯狂了
- Oh, my God. - Jim, I... This...
天呐  吉姆  我  这...
I had it under control.
我已经控制住局面了
Yeah, sure you did.
没错啊
[HOPPER GRUNTS]
[JOYCE] What are you doing?
你在干什么
I'm improvising.
临场发挥
♪ Your love ♪
♪ Liftin' me higher... ♪
Jesus, how far is this place, man?
天  这地方到底有多远  兄弟
Relax, we're almost there.
放轻松  我们快到了
Suzie must be pretty special, huh?
苏茜一定很特别吧
I mean, if you built this thing
如果你造了这东西
and lugged it all the way to the middle of nowhere
再大老远的把这东西拖到荒郊野岭
just to talk to her?
就为了跟她说话
I mean, nobody's scientifically perfect,
没有真正完美的人
but Suzie's about as close to being perfect
但苏茜比任何人都
as any human could possibly be.
无限趋近于完美
She sound made-up to me.
我觉得他是瞎编的
She sound made-up to you?
你觉得呢
- Why are you hesitating, Steve? - I'm... I'm... I'm not! I'm not!
-你干吗迟疑  史蒂夫  -我  我没有
I think she sounds real. You know, totally, absolutely real.
我觉得挺真实的  绝对的  完全真实
Left. Turn left.
左  左转
- There's not a road here. - Turn left now!
-左边根本没有路  -立马左转
[STEVE] Jesus! Hang on!
我的天  抓紧了
♪ Higher and higher ♪
Whoa! Henderson, where are we going?!
亨德森  你在搞什么
Up!
上啊
Whoa!
♪ Liftin' me higher... ♪
- Oh, Jesus! - We're not gonna make it!
我的天呐  -我们上不去的
Yes, we are. Come on, baby. Come on, baby!
上得去  加油  宝贝  加油啊
[CAR ENGINE STRAINING]
[STEVE] Come on!
别这样
[STEVE GRUNTS] Come on. Come on.
不要  不要
[STEVE] Come on!
不要啊
Guess the Toddfather has its limitations.
看来托德老爹也有能力不足的时候
[STEVE PANTING]
[ENGINE STOPS]
[DRAMATIC SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[CAR DOORS SHUTTING]
[MIKE, ON RADIO] Scoops Troop, do you copy?
冰淇淋小分队  收到请回答
- Scoops Troop, do you copy? - [RADIO STATIC HISSING]
[MIKE] Scoops Troop, do you copy?
冰淇淋小分队  收到请回答
Scoops Troop, I repeat, do you copy?
冰淇淋小分队  我重复  收到请回答
We're trapped in the mall and in need of emergency transportation.
我们被困在商场里了 需要紧急转移
[MIKE] Scoops Troop, do you copy? Billy has found us.
冰淇淋小分队  收到请回答  比利找到我们了
He has disabled our car and we are trapped in the mall.
他毁了我们的车  我们被困在商场里了
Repeat: Billy has disabled our car and we are trapped in the mall.
重复一遍  比利把我们的车毁了
- Scoops Troop... - You're gonna kill him, aren't you?
你要杀了他  是不是
This is just a precaution, okay?
这些都只是以防万一
And not just against Billy.
不只是针对比利
If he knows we're here, so does the Mind Flayer.
他能知道我们在这  那么吸灵魔也知道
Scoops Troop, I repeat, we are in need of emergency transportation.
冰淇淋小分队  我重复 我们需要紧急转移
- Do you copy? - [RADIO STATIC HISSING]
收到请回答
Scoops Troop, do you copy?
冰淇淋小分队  收到请回答
No chance that thing'll drive, right?
那辆车应该不能开了吧
- [MIKE] Steve, do you copy? - We don't need it to drive.
-史蒂夫  能听见吗  -我们不需要开它
[MIKE] Dustin!
达斯汀
We just need the ignition cable.
我们只需要它的点火电缆
[ALL STRAINING]
[JONATHAN] Push!
推啊
[METAL SQUEALING]
[STRAINING CONTINUES]
- [GLASS SHATTERS] - [WILL] Shit!
操
Let me try.
让我试试
[PANTING] El...
一一
[SIGHS]
I can do it.
我可以的
[MIKE SIGHS]
- [LOW FREQUENCY VIBRATION] - [METAL BUCKLING]
[GASPS]
[METAL SQUEALING]
[STRAINED BREATHS]
[PANTING]
[VIBRATION INTENSIFIES]
[YELLS]
[FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING RUSSIAN ON PA]
[BRAKES SQUEALING]
[IN RUSSIAN] Can I help?
有什么事吗
[IN RUSSIAN] Picking up.
来拿东西
Do I know you?
我认识你吗
New arrivals.
新来的
Landed last night.
昨天晚上刚到
Say goodbye to sunlight.
向阳光说再见吧
Who needs sunlight
当我们已有彼此
when we have one another, comrade?
谁还需要阳光  同志
[CHUCKLES] Indeed, comrade!
确实  同志
And a bottle of Stolichnaya.
还有一瓶苏联红牌伏特加
[BOTH LAUGHING]
[LOUD BEEPING]
[MURRAY AND GUARD CONTINUE LAUGHING]
[MURRAY CHUCKLES]
[LOUD BEEPING]
Why are you talking so much?
你干吗说这么多废话
He was nice.
他人还不错
- He was nice? - He was a nice guard.
-人还不错  -他是个不错的守卫
Yeah, I mean, we should probably invite him
是啊  等着一切结束了
over after all this is done.
我们应该邀请他来玩
[JOYCE] Yeah, I can bake him a casserole.
是啊  我可以拿砂锅烤了他
[HOPPER] Get a six-pack, share some laughs.
拿点酒  分享一下快乐
- You know, have a drink. - [MURRAY SEETHES]
你懂的  喝一杯
Ugh.
Anyone wanna trade jobs?
有人想交换任务吗
[DUSTIN ON RADIO] Bald Eagle, do you copy?
秃鹰小分队  收到请回答
Bald Eagle, I repeat, this is Scoops Troop, do you copy?
秃鹰小分队  我重复 这里是冰淇淋小分队  收到请回答
Yes, I copy.
收到
[ALL CHUCKLE WITH RELIEF]
Call sign?
呼号是
[SCOFFS]
Bald Eagle.
秃鹰小分队
Please repeat.
请重复
- Bald Eagle. This is Bald Eagle! - [DUSTIN] Copy that.
-秃鹰  这里是秃鹰小分队  -收到
Good to hear your voice, Bald Eagle. What's your 20?
很高兴能听到你的声音 秃鹰小分队  你们到哪了
We reached the vent. I'll contact you when I need you.
我们已抵达通风口  有需要我会联系你们的
Until then, silence.
在此之前  保持安静
Roger that, Bald Eagle.
收到  秃鹰小分队
This is Scoops Troop, going radio silent. 10-10, over.
这里是冰淇淋  即将沉默  好运  完毕
I hate children.
我讨厌小孩子
[MURRAY GROANS]
- Remember, if anyone says anything, just... - Smile and nod.
-记住  有人说话只需要  -点头微笑
[SIGHS] Good luck.
好运
[ALL STRAINING]
[JONATHAN] Push!
推
[METAL SQUEALING]
[GRUNTING, PANTING]
[JONATHAN] All right, great.
好的  太棒了
All right, now, all the way. Ready?
现在大家一起  准备好了吗
Three, two, one... Push!
三二一  推
[ALL STRAINING]
Told you.
跟你说了
Physics.
学好物理
How do we get it open?
我们要怎么打开这个
Uh, there should be a latch. Check under the wheel.
应该有个门闩  检查一下方向盘底下
- [JONATHAN] You see it? - [NANCY] I don't know, hold on.
-看见没  -我不知道  等等
What's she doing?
她在干什么
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
[HIGH FREQUENCY VIBRATION]
[VIBRATION INTENSIFIES]
- [MIKE, ECHOING] El. - [VIBRATION STOPS]
一一
Are you okay?
你还好吗
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[JONATHAN GRUNTS]
- [NANCY] Do you see it? - I don't know.
-你找到了吗  -我不知道
It should be right here.
应该就在这里
Distributor, distributor...
配电盘  配电盘
[FLUTTERING SOUND]
[DISTANT RUMBLING]
[POUNDING FOOTSTEPS]
Mike.
迈克
[SKYLIGHT GLASS CLINKING]
[FOOTSTEPS CONTINUE]
[GASPS]
Got it.
找到了
Nancy!
南茜
[CREATURE SNARLING]
[MIKE] Come on!
快走
[GLASS SHATTERING]
[SHRIEKING]
[SNARLING]
[ROARING]
[DRAMATIC SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[IN RUSSIAN] We just found them like this.
我们刚发现他们已经死了
[IN RUSSIAN] The American.
美国人
It's taking too long.
时间太久了
- It's fine. - No, it's not. It is not.
-没事的  -不  有事  有事
She could've died back there.
她很可能会死
She almost did.
她差点就死了
Well, she's safe now. She's on her way to Murray's.
现在她安全了  她在去莫里家的路上
That thing won't find her,
只有我们把它杀死
not before we kill it.
那东西才不会找到她
Hey. This isn't the way this is supposed to work, all right?
不应该是这个样子的  好吗
You're supposed to say, "Yes, I told you so.
你应该说  "对  我跟你说过的
That's why we needed to go back to the kids."
所以我们才需要回到孩子身边去"
Oh, yeah, and then you say something like...
没错  然后你会说
[AS HOPPER] "Yeah, well, it's really hard to listen
"如果你把一切事情都说的
when you make everything sound like
好像世界末日要来临那样绝望
it's the end of the goddamn world."
真的会很难受"
[GENTLE RUSSIAN BALLAD PLAYING]
You know...
你知道
I think, despite everything, I mean, despite the arguing,
我想不管怎么样  即便有很多争吵
I think we make a pretty good team.
我还是觉得我们的合作很棒
[CLICKS TONGUE]
Well, we made it this far, didn't we?
我们都走到这里了  对不对
[JOYCE SIGHS]
Yeah.
没错
We did.
的确
So, uh...
所以
did I get the job or what?
我到底能不能得到这份工作
Ah, come on.
拜托
Detective Byers.
拜耶斯警探
It has a ring, doesn't it?
有个戒指的  对吧
It's kinda hard to serve in a town where you don't live, Detective.
警探  不住这里住还要管这里的事可有点难
[CLICKS TONGUE]
You're still moving outta here. I mean, that is the plan, right?
你还是打算要搬走  你计划好了吧
[SIGHS] Eh, we'll see how it goes.
我们看看后续情况如何吧
"How it goes"? How what goes?
"后续情况如何"  什么情况
You know, if... if we actually do make it out of here,
你知道  如果我们可以能成功离开这里
we... we deserve to celebrate, right?
我们值得庆祝一下  对吧
Yeah.
嗯
I mean...
我是说
yes.
是的
Absolutely.
绝对需要
I hear Enzo's is pretty good.
听说恩佐餐厅很不错
What do you say, Friday, eight o'clock?
你觉得呢  周五八点钟如何
Uh, El likes to watch Miami Vice on Fridays.
一一周五喜欢看《迈阿密风云》
It... It starts at 10:00, so I... I can't be out late on a Friday.
十点开始  所以周五晚上我不能在外面待很晚
Okay, well, how about 7:00, then?
那就七点如何
7:00?
七点
Enzo's, Friday, I meet you there?
恩佐餐厅  周五咱们那里见
No, you pick me up.
不行  你得去接我
Picking you up, 7:00 p.m. Friday.
周五晚七点去接你
Yeah, it's a date.
嗯  那就约[约会]好了
[INHALES SHARPLY]
Just for clarification, just because I... I mean, just... If...
先澄清一下  因为我...如果...要是...
When you say "date", just so that we're crystal clear,
你说"约会"  所以我要说得清清楚楚
- so there's no confusion... Yeah? - Yeah, Hop?
-这样不会有误会  怎么  -没错  霍普
Stop talking or I'm gonna change my mind.
别说了  不然我要改主意了
Yeah, okay. Yeah.
行  好的  行
Okay.
行
[RUSSIAN BALLAD CRESCENDOS]
[GRUNTS]
- [RADIO BEEPS] - [SIGHS]
Scoops Troop, this is...
冰淇淋小分队  我是
Hm.
Bald Eagle.
秃鹰
[MURRAY] I've reached another junction.
我到达了另一个交叉口
- [DUSTIN] This is what? - The fourth junction.
-是什么  -第四交叉口
All right, so if memory serves,
好吧  如果我没记错的话
this is right after the My Little Pony thesis.
讲完小马宝莉论题后我们到了这里
- We went left, so he has to go right. - Right.
-我们去了左边  所以他必须去右边  -右边
Fly right, Bald Eagle.
向右飞  秃鹰
- [DUSTIN] Fly right. - Roger that, flying right.
-向右飞  -收到  向右飞行
Little shit.
小混蛋
[ROBIN] What's the My Little Pony thesis?
小马宝莉论题是什么
[ERICA] Don't get him started.
别让他说这个
- Get him started? Just tell me... - Hey, guys?
-让他说这个  告诉我  -各位
[OMINOUS SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
Griswold Family, this is Scoops Troop! Do you copy? Over!
格里斯沃尔德一家  这里是冰淇淋小分队 收到吗  完毕
Griswold Family, I repeat, this is Scoops Troop. Do you...
格里斯沃尔德一家  重复一遍 这里是冰淇淋小分队  收到...
[CREATURE SHRIEKS ON RADIO]
Griswold Family, do you copy?
格里斯沃尔德一家  收到吗
Do you copy?!
收到吗
[ROARING]
[DUSTIN] Griswold Family, this is Scoops Troop.
格里斯沃尔德一家  这里是冰淇淋小分队
Please confirm your safety!
请确认你方安全
Griswold Family, this is Scoops Troop! Please confirm your safety!
你们在去秃鹰老巢的路上吗 请确认你方安全
Are you en route to Bald Eagle's nest?
有谁快点应答一下  有人在吗
- [DUSTIN CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY] - [CREATURE ROARING]
Please confirm your safety!
Someone, please just answer. Is anyone there?
- [WILL SHUDDERS] - Just answer!
快回答
- Anyone, please... - [RADIO TRANSMISSION GARBLES]
有人吗...
[ELEVEN PANTING]
[SNARLING]
[GROWLING]
[CHITTERING NOISE]
[ROARING]
[PANTING]
[DISTORTED TRANSMISSION] Griswold Family, do you copy?
格里斯沃尔德一家  收到吗
Griswold Family, do you copy?
[SNARLING SOUNDS ON RADIO]
[DUSTIN] Do you copy?!
收到吗
- Where are you going?! - To get them the hell outta there!
-你们去哪里  -去帮他们逃离那里
Stay here, contact the others!
待在这里  跟其他人保持联系
- Shit. - Wait, Robin!
-该死  -等等  罗宾
Stay in touch.
保持联络
Got it.
没问题
Bald Eagle, this is Scoops Troop. What's your 20?
秃鹰  这里是冰淇淋小分队  你们在哪里
I told you, radio silence!
跟你说过了  没有回复
Yeah, but we have a problem.
是的  但我们遇到一个问题
What kind of problem?
什么样的问题
[ROARING]
[HISSING AND SNARLING]
[SNARLING]
[CREATURE GROWLING]
[SQUELCHING FOOTSTEPS]
[SNARLING]
[PANTING]
[GROWLING]
It's turned away. If we go up the stairs now, we'll make it.
它转身了  如果我们现在上楼  就能成功
- No way, not with El's leg. - We have to try.
-不可能  一一的腿这样  -我们得试试
There's another way...
还有另外一条
to get out.
出去的路
Through the Gap.
从GAP过去
[SNARLING]
[MIKE PANTING]
[WHISPERS] Okay.
好的
Now.
就现在
[ALL PANTING]
[DRAMATIC SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[BROKEN GLASS CLINKING]
[MAX GASPS]
[ROARS]
[SCREECHING AND GROWLING]
[SNARLING]
[SCREECHING]
[TENTACLE SCREECHING]
[SNARLING]
[TENTACLE CHITTERS, SCREECHES]
[ROARS]
[CREATURE SNARLS]
[PANTING]
Bald Eagle has landed.
秃鹰已经着陆
Repeat. [PANTING]
重复一遍
Bald Eagle
秃鹰已经着陆
has landed.
[SIGHS]
Okay.
好的
Come on, how much longer?
拜托  还要多久
I don't know, I've never done this before!
我不知道  我之前也没做过
Okay.
好吧
Okay, okay!
好吧  行吧
Get ready, lovebirds, you're almost up to bat.
准备好吧  小情侣们  你们要准备上场了
[CREATURE LOWING]
[TENTACLE SQUEALING]
[TENTACLE CHITTERS, SNARLS]
[SCREECHING]
[ALARM BLARING]
[INDISTINCT RUSSIAN CHATTER]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[POWERING DOWN NOISE]
- [BUZZER SOUNDS] - [ALARM BLARING]
- [CREATURE SNARLS] - Oh, shit.
该死
[PANTING]
- What are you doing? - Don't worry.
-你在干什么  -别担心
[HISSING]
[TENTACLE SCREECHES]
[SCREECHING]
[SNARLS]
[TENTACLE SQUEALS]
[JONATHAN] Go! Go, go, go, go, go, go!
快快快快快快快
[MIKE] Let's go.
快走
- [ALARM BLARING] - [INDISTINCT FEMALE VOICE ON PA]
Let's go.
快走
[SOLDIERS YELLING IN RUSSIAN]
[IN RUSSIAN] Did Mikhail send for you?
米哈伊尔派你们来的吗
[FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING RUSSIAN ON PA]
[JOYCE GASPS]
- All right. - Okay.
-好了  -好吧
- Give me the code. - Okay.
把密码告诉我
Six-six-two,
six-oh-eight,
oh-oh-four.
[PANEL BEEPS]
[STRAINING]
[GASPS]
Uh...
again?
再来
Six-six-two,
six-oh-eight,
oh-oh-four.
[PANEL BEEPS]
Murray?
莫里
Your goddamn code...
你的密码
is wrong.
不对
What? Are you sure?
什么  你确定吗
Yeah, I'm sure.
我确定
Well, I... I suppose it could be wrong.
也可能是错的
How could it be wrong?
怎么可能是错的
[MURRAY] The code is a number, a famous number.
密码是个著名的数字
Planck's constant I... I thought I knew it.
普朗克常数  我以为我背住了
- [MURRAY AND HOPPER ARGUE] - Planck's constant.
普朗克常数
- You know it? - Not by heart. You?
-你知道吗  -记不住  你呢
I'm not a nerd, nerd.
我不是书呆子  书呆子
[MURRAY] He told me it was Planck's constant, which I know.
他说是普朗克常数  我记得的
Why would I need him to give me a number I already know?
我为什么要让他告诉我我已经知道的数
[STATIC HISSING]
What are you doing?
你在干什么
[RADIO STATIC WHINES]
[JONATHAN] Go, go, go!
跑跑跑
[BILLY'S CAR ENGINE REVS]
[LOUD REVVING]
- Shit. - Get the car started. Go!
该死  启动汽车  快
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. Come on.
不不不  拜托了
[ENGINE REVS]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Come on. - We gotta go!
快  我们得走了
Come on!
快
We gotta go!
我们得走了
[GASPS]
[INTENSE SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[PANTING]
Are you okay?
你没事吧
Ask me tomorrow?
明天再问我
[CREATURE SNARLING]
[ROBIN GASPS]
Oh, shit!
该死
[SNARLING AND GROWLING]
[ROARING]
[CAR HORN HONKING]
Get in!
上车
[ROARING]
- [LUCAS] Go, go, go, go! - [STEVE] Go, go, go!
跑跑跑
[CREATURE SCREECHES]
[ROARING]
[CRICKETS CHIRPING]
[DISTANT DOG BARKING]
犹他州  盐湖城
[RADIO STATIC CRACKLING]
- [DUSTIN] Suzie, do you copy? - [GASPS]
苏茜  你收到吗
Suzie, do you copy?
This is Suzie. I copy.
我是苏茜  我收到了
- Suzie! - Dusty-bun?
-苏茜  -达斯宝贝
"Dusty-bun"?
"达斯宝贝"
Where have you been?
你去哪了
I'm so, so sorry. I... I've been really busy...
真抱歉  我太忙了
uh, trying to save the world from Russians and monsters.
我在努力从苏联人和怪物手中拯救世界
[CHUCKLES] Of course you have.
当然了
Get the goddamn number already!
快问数字
Who was that?
那是谁
[STAMMERS] It was...
是...
Uh, I don't know, actually. I think it was just some interference.
我不知道  好像是干扰
So, why don't we, uh, change frequency
我们把频率改到
to 14.158?
14.158吧
Copy that, shifting frequency. Standby.
收到  换频道  等待
[RADIO WHINES]
[PANTING]
- [SUZIE] Dusty-bun, you copy? - [DUSTIN] I copy, Suzie-poo.
-达斯宝贝  收到吗  -收到  苏茜宝
It sounds much better now, thanks.
现在清晰多了  谢谢
- [BOTH] Suzie. - Okay, so, listen,
-苏茜  -听着
do you know Planck's constant?
你知道普朗克常数吗
Do you know the Earth orbits the sun?
你知道地球环绕太阳吗
[SNICKERS] Okay, so I know it starts with two sixes, and then a...
好  我知道是6开头的  然后...
W-What is it?
是什么来着
Okay, let me just be clear on this.
我想理清楚
I haven't heard from you in a week,
我一周没你的消息了
and now you want a mathematical equation that you should know
现在你想问一个你该知道的
so you can... save the world?
数学等式  好去拯救世界吗
Suzie-poo, I promise,
苏茜宝  我保证
I will make it up to you as soon as possible.
我会尽快弥补你的
You can make it up to me now.
你现在就弥补我吧
- What? - I want to hear it.
-什么  -我想听
- Not right now. - Yes, now, Dusty-bun.
-现在不行  -就现在  达斯宝贝
Suzie-poo, this is urgent.
苏茜宝  这是急事
Yes, yes, you're saving the world, I heard you the first time,
是啊  你在拯救世界  我听到了
but Ged is also saving Earthsea
但格德也在拯救地海
and he's about to confront the shadow,
他就要面对影魔了
so this is Suzie, signing off.
所以苏茜通话结束
Wait, wait, wait! Okay.
等等  好吧
Okay. Okay.
好
Shit.
该死
[SIGHS]
♪ Turn around ♪
*转过身*
♪ Look at what you see ♪
*看你看到什么*
♪ In her face ♪
*她的脸上*
- ♪ The mirror of your dreams ♪ - [SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
*映射了你的梦*
[SUZIE AND DUSTIN HARMONIZE] ♪ Make believe I'm everywhere ♪
*让我相信自己无所不在*
♪ Given in the light ♪
*沐浴在荣光之中*
♪ Written on the pages is ♪
*书页上写着*
♪ The answer to ♪
*永不尽的*
♪ A never-ending story ♪
*故事的答案*
[SUZIE AND DUSTIN VOCALIZING]
♪ Reach the stars ♪
*冲向星空*
♪ Fly a fantasy ♪
*为幻梦飞行*
[SINGING SOUNDS ON RADIO] ♪ Dream a dream ♪
*梦我所梦*
♪ And what you see will be ♪
*你的设想会成为现实*
♪ Rhymes that keep their secrets will ♪
*旋律将保守他们的秘密*
♪ Unfold behind the clouds ♪
*在云彩后揭开*
♪ And there upon a rainbow is ♪
*在那彩虹之上*
♪ The answer to a never-ending story ♪
*永不尽的故事的答案*
[SUZIE AND DUSTIN VOCALIZING]
♪ Story ♪
*故事*
[SUZIE AND DUSTIN VOCALIZING]
[CHUCKLES]
Planck's constant is 6.62607004.
普朗克常数是6.62607004
[PANTING]
[KEYPAD BEEPS]
You just saved the world.
你刚拯救了世界
[SIGHS]
Gosh, I miss you, Dusty-bun.
天呐  我好想你  达斯宝贝
And I miss you more, Suzie-poo.
我更想你  苏茜宝
I miss you more, multiplied by all the stars in our galaxy.
我更想你  乘以全银河系的星星
[DUSTIN] No, I miss you...
-不  我想你...  -够了
Enough.
[STATIC HISSING]
[OMINOUS SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[BILLY COUGHS]
[GROANS]
[GRUNTS]
[BUZZER SOUNDING]
- Shit! - Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
该死  跑跑跑
[PANTING]
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
[CREATURE SHRIEKS]
It's turning around.
它调头了
- What? - It's turning around!
-什么  -它调头了
Maybe we wore it out.
或许我们把它跑累了
I don't think so. Hold on.
我觉得不是  坐稳
[ROBIN SCREAMS]
[STRAINING]
[ALL PANTING]
[ELEVEN GROANS]
[ALARM BLARING]
[MEN YELLING IN RUSSIAN]
[YELLING IN RUSSIAN]
Hey! Everybody out.
都出去
Everybody out!
[SCIENTISTS CLAMORING]
Hey.
You ready to end this?
你准备好了结一切了吗
[MIKE] In here. In here.
这里  进去
Okay. Come on, come on, come on...
好  快快快
Billy.
比利
[MAX] Billy, you don't have to do this.
比利  你不用这样的
Billy. Your name's Billy, Billy Hargrove.
比利  你叫比利  比利·哈格罗夫
You live on 4819 Cherry Lane. Billy, please, I'm Max, I'm your...
你住在樱桃巷4819号  比利  求你 我是麦克斯  我是你...
- [BILLY YELLS] - [MIKE GRUNTS]
[BILLY YELLS]
[YELLS]
[ELEVEN GRUNTS, YELPS]
[BILLY GRUNTS]
Murray, you all set down there?
莫里  你准备好了吗
All set, but I've got some company which I'd love you to obliterate.
好了  但我这里来人了 我希望你能消灭他们
Will do. Hang tight.
没问题  等着
[BEEPING]
On three.
数到三
好
One...
一
[JOYCE EXHALES]
Two...
二
[HOPPER GROANS]
[GASPS]
[JOYCE YELPS, GRUNTS]
[JOYCE SQUEALS, PANTS]
- [JOYCE SCREAMS] - [GRIGORI GRUNTS]
[JOYCE YELPS IN PAIN]
[IN RUSSIAN] The Americans,
美国人
I've found them...
我找到他们了
[HOPPER YELLS]
[HOPPER GROANS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[FIGHTING GRUNTS]
[HOPPER GRUNTS, GROANS]
[BILLY WHISPERS] Don't be afraid.
别怕
It'll be over soon.
快结束了
Just try and stay... very still.
尽量  别动
[CREATURE SNARLING]
[RUMBLING FOOTSTEP]
[SNARLING]
[WHIMPERING]
[GASPING]
[LOWING AND GROWLING]
[HISSING]
[SCREECHING]
[CREATURE WAILS]
Flay this, you ugly piece of shit!
吸这个啊  你个混蛋
[SCREECHING]
[FIREWORKS CRACKLING]
[STEVE] Hey, asshole! Over here! [GRUNTS]
混蛋  过来
[GROANS]
[HOPPER YELLS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[HOPPER GROANS, GRUNTS]
[GRIGORI YELLS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[PANTING]
[GRUNTS]
[CREATURE WAILS]
- [GROANS] - [GRUNTS]
[GROANS]
[SCREECHING]
[BILLY GROANS]
[HOPPER GROANS]
[GRIGORI YELLS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[SCREECHING IN PAIN]
- [FIREWORKS WHISTLING] - [BILLY SCREAMS]
[PANTING]
[ELEVEN SCREAMS]
[SCREAMING]
[CREATURE ROARING]
[PANTING]
[CONSOLE BEEPING]
[HOPPER YELLS]
[GRIGORI GROANS]
- [WAILS] - [HOPPER GRUNTS]
[GRIGORI GRUNTS]
[CREATURE SNARLING]
- We're almost out! - I know!
-我们快没弹药了  -我知道
Dustin! We're out of time!
达斯汀  我们没时间了
Hurry! Close it now!
快  快关上
[DUSTIN] Close it!
关上
[CONSOLE BEEPING]
[STRAINING]
Come on!
加油啊
Mike...
迈克
Mike.
Mike. Mike. Mike, get up. Mike, can you hear me? Mike! Mike!
迈克  迈克  起来  你听得到吗  迈克
[MIKE WHIMPERS]
[MAX] Hey, come on.
过来
You okay?
你没事吧
Where's El?
一一呢
[ROARING]
[PANTING]
- [WINCES] - [ELEVEN WHIMPERS]
[ELEVEN SCREAMS]
[LAUGHING]
- [YOUNG BILLY] Leave me alone! - Stop it!
别管我  住手
- Mom! - [BILLY'S DAD] This is your new sister.
-妈妈  -这是你的新妹妹
[YOUNG BILLY]... at least seven feet.
至少有两米高
[DISTORTED SCREAMING]
Seven... feet. [GASPS]
两米
[FIREWORKS CRACKLING]
[GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING]
You told her...
你对她说
the wave was seven feet.
浪有两米高
[BILLY'S MOM] Woo!
Yeah! [LAUGHS]
好啊
[ELEVEN CRIES]
You ran to her, on the beach.
你在海滩上跑向她
[LAUGHING]
There were seagulls.
还有海鸥
[SQUAWKING]
She wore a hat...
她戴了顶帽子
[BILLY SNIFFLES]
... with a blue ribbon.
系着蓝色缎带
[BILLY GASPS]
[ELEVEN] A long dress...
长裙子
with a blue and red flower.
上面有红蓝色的花
Yell... Yellow sandals,
黄拖鞋
covered in sand.
上面都是沙子
She was pretty.
她很漂亮
[LAUGHING]
She was really pretty.
她真的很漂亮
And you...
你...
you were happy.
你很开心
[LAUGHING]
[STRAINING]
[HOPPER GROANS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[GRIGORI SCREAMS]
[HOPPER GRUNTS]
[GRIGORI WAILS]
I'll see you in hell!
地狱见
- [GRIGORI GRUNTS] - [HOPPER GASPS]
[ELECTRICITY WHOOSHING]
[FIREWORKS WHISTLING AND CRACKLING]
[NANCY] Hit me.
来吧
[GRUNTS]
[ROARING]
We're out!
没了
Damn it!
该死
[ROARING]
[SNARLING]
[ROARING CONTINUES]
[SCREECHING]
[SNARLING AND ROARING]
[BILLY] No!
不
[BILLY YELLS]
[CREATURE SCREECHING]
[YELLS]
[CREATURE SHRIEKING]
[SCREAMS IN PAIN]
[CREATURE SCREECHES]
[BILLY SCREAMS]
Close it now!
快关上
Close it!
关上
[DRAMATIC SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[JOYCE STRAINING]
[ROARING]
[SCREAMS]
Billy!
比利
[BILLY GRUNTS]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[SCREECHING]
[SNARLING]
[ROARING]
[GROANING]
[DRAMATIC SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[WEAK SNARLING SOUND]
[PANTING]
- El. - Mike!
-一一  -迈克
[ELEVEN SOBS AND WHIMPERS]
Billy?
比利
[COUGHING]
Billy.
比利  比利  起来啊  比利  求你
Billy, Billy, get up, please. Billy, get up, please, please.
- I'm sorry. - Billy...
-对不起  -比利
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Billy. Billy.
比利  比利
Billy, wake up. Billy, get up. Please, Billy...
比利  醒醒  求你  比利
[SOBS] Billy!
比利
Billy... [SNIFFLES]
Billy...
- I'm sorry. - [SOBBING]
对不起
It's okay. It's okay.
没事了
[CRYING]
[SOBBING] Hop.
霍普
Jim. Where's Jim?
吉姆  吉姆呢
[JOYCE GASPS]
[YELLING IN RUSSIAN]
[HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING]
[SOLDIER] Let's go! Go! Come on!
我们走  快
[SOLDIERS YELLING INDISTINCTLY]
You all right?
你没事吧
[SOLDIERS YELLING] Hands up!
举起手来
Don't shoot! American! We're Americans! Americans!
别开枪  美国人  我们是美国人
[SOLDIERS YELLING INDISTINCTLY]
[OMINOUS SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[SIRENS WAILING]
Hey, come on, let's go!
我们走
Go, go!
快走
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
[SIRENS WAILING]
[EMOTIONAL SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[JOYCE SOBS]
[JOYCE] Thank God!
谢天谢地
- [HELICOPTERS FLYING OVERHEAD] - [SOBBING]
三个月后
[NEWS FANFARE PLAYING]
顶尖新闻
[MALE REPORTER] Welcome to Hawkins, Indiana,
欢迎来到印第安纳州霍金斯
a wonderful place to grow up,
这个好地方适合成长
to raise your family,
抚养家庭
to walk your dog.
遛狗
- But then... - [SIRENS WAILING]
但是
... on July Fourth, everything changed.
国庆节那天  风云突变
A terrible tragedy struck this small town.
一场重大惨剧降临小镇
丑闻震惊小镇
三人死亡
But this was not this small town's first brush with tragedy.
但这不是小镇第一次遭遇惨剧了
英雄局长死于大火
镇民要求主持正义
Mysterious deaths, government cover-ups,
神秘死亡  政府掩盖
睿侠月度员工
政府腐败  据称掩盖事件后  小镇陷入悲痛
a bizarre chemical leak.
一场奇怪的化学品泄漏
化学品泄漏
Is it all linked?
都有关联吗
All a vast conspiracy?
都是巨大的阴谋吗
阴谋
The fault of a disgraced, corrupt mayor?
是否全怪一位腐败倒台的镇长
镇长被攻击
Or is something more going on in the heartland?
还是说中心地带发生了更大的事
- Can a town itself be cursed? - [WOMAN SCREAMS]
欢迎来到霍金斯地狱
Some believe a rise in Satanism is to blame.
这个小镇会是被诅咒了吗
龙与地下城
地下城法师指导
- [EERIE CACKLING LAUGHTER] - To find out,
想知道真相
tune in tonight at 8:00 p.m. for "Horror in the Heartland"
今晚8点请收看《中心地带恐怖事件》
on Cutting Edge.
尽在顶尖新闻
家庭音像
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
You put your mom down as a reference?
你拿你妈当推荐人
Yeah. Why not? She's, like, super well-respected.
是啊  怎么不行  她非常受尊敬的
[ROBIN] You're such a dingus.
你真是个呆瓜
[STEVE] Wha...
什么...
[ROBIN] Uh, just to be clear, we weren't fired, you know.
说清楚  我们不是被解雇的
The mall burned down and, like, killed a bunch of people.
商场烧毁了  还死了好几个人
Thanks for sharing. Didn't know.
多谢告知  我不知道呢
Three favorite movies. Go.
三部最喜欢电影  说
Uh... The Apartment,
《桃色公寓》
Hidden Fortress, Children of Paradise.
《隐秘堡垒》《天堂的孩子》
You, go.
你  说
- Favorite movies? - Did I stutter?
-最爱电影吗  -我口吃了吗
- Uh... Animal House, for sure. - [ROBIN SCOFFS]
《动物屋》绝对的
Um...
Eyes on me, Harrington.
看着我  哈灵顿
Yeah. Uh...
嗯
Star Wars.
《星战》
A New Hope?
《新希望》吗
A new what-now?
什么
Which Star Wars?
哪部《星战》
The one with the teddy bears. Duh. [SQUEALS LIKE AN EWOK]
有泰迪熊的那个呗
No? Uh...
没有吗  刚出来那部
Oh, the one that just came out. The movie that just came out.
刚出来的那部电影
The one with the DeLorean and Alex P. Keaton,
就是有德洛雷安和艾利克斯·基顿的那部
and he's trying to bang his mom. [CHUCKLES]
他想上他老妈
The time...
时间
Yeah, those are my top three. Classics.
那是我最喜欢的三部  经典
You start Monday.
你星期一来
You start never.
你永远别来
Will you just, um... Will you give us a minute?
可以  给我们点时间吗
Why?
为什么
Steve.
史蒂夫
- [YANKS RESUME AGGRESSIVELY] - [ROBIN SCOFFS]
All right, you have to understand, Keith,
好吧  你得明白  基斯
I know his taste is a bit pedestrian,
我知道他的品位比较俗
but the dingus has other qualities.
但呆瓜有其他优点
He's a douchebag of the highest order, Robin.
他就是最高级别的蠢蛋  罗宾
He was a bit of a prick to us in high school, I'll grant you that,
他在高中时的确对我们很差 我承认
but he remains..
但他现在仍是
a total chick magnet.
女生磁铁
Yeah, okay, and this is relevant to me how?
是啊  那跟我有什么关系
Uh, Earth to Keith.
地球呼叫基斯
The ladies will come in just to see him.
女士们会专为见他而走进来
They'll come in in droves.
她们会成群地来
Droves, Keith.
成群  基斯
We sold so much ice cream,
我们当初冰淇淋卖得太火
they had to get a second shipment in from Michigan.
他们不得不从密歇根二次进货
Goddamn Michigan, Keith.
密歇根州啊  基斯
And these ladies... [INHALES SHARPLY]
那些女人
These ladies are hot.
那些女人都很性感
They're so very hot.
她们可性感了
And there are too many of them for little Steve.
史蒂夫一个人应付不来
He needs assistance.
他需要协助
He needs your assistance, Keith.
他需要你的协助  基斯
What's in it for you? You got a thing for him or something?
你有什么好处  你喜欢他吗
[STEVE] Goddammit. This is...
该死  这...
Hm.
We're just, um...
我们只是...
We're just friends.
我们只是朋友
Oh!
Fast Times. Fast Times. Ever heard of it?
《开放的美国学府》  听说过吗
- Top three for me, Keith. - [LAUGHS]
我的最爱三部之一  基斯
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! Slow down. - Sorry. Sorry.
-慢点  -抱歉
- Still got it? - Yeah, yeah.
-还行吗  -嗯
搬家公司
[MAX AND LUCAS] ♪ Turn around ♪
*转过身*
待售
♪ Look at what you see ♪
*看你看到什么*
♪ In her face ♪
*她的脸上*
♪ The mirror of your dreams ♪
*映射了你的梦*
♪ Rhymes that keep their secrets ♪
*旋律将保守他们的秘密*
♪ Will unfold behind the clouds ♪
*在云彩后揭开*
Wait, did we get that verse right? It's "unfold behind the clouds"?
等等  我们唱得对吗 是"在云彩后揭开"吗
Yeah, but you're butchering it, so could you please stop?
对  但你们都唱毁了  能不能停下
So then join in, Dusty-bun. [BLOWS AIR KISS]
那就一起唱  达斯宝贝
Yeah, come on, Dusty-bun, why don't you join us?
是啊  达斯宝贝  一起唱嘛
You guys are so funny, you should be on Carson.
你们真好笑  该去上《卡森秀》
- Can't we just hear your rendition? - No.
-不能听你唱一遍吗  -不能
Please? Just one verse?
求你  就一段
No. No way. It's reserved for Suzie's ears and Suzie's ears alone.
不要  那是只唱给苏茜听的
♪ Turn around ♪
*转过身*
♪ Look at what you see ♪
*看你看到什么*
- ♪ In their face ♪ - [LUCAS CLAPS]
*她的脸上*
♪ The mirror of your dreams ♪
*映射了你的梦*
[DUSTIN] Shut up, you guys.
你们闭嘴啦
♪ Rhymes that keep their secrets ♪
*旋律将保守他们的秘密*
[DUSTIN] Stop! You guys, please, shut up.
闭嘴  你们闭嘴吧
龙与地下城
Whoa, dude. That's the donation box.
哥们  那是捐赠箱
I know. I'll just use yours when I come back.
我知道  等我回来用你的好了
I mean, if we still wanna play.
如果我们还玩的话
Yeah, but what if you want to join another party?
好啊  如果你想跟别人一起玩呢
Not possible.
不会的
[CHUCKLES]
[JONATHAN SIGHS]
Is that...
都...
everything?
搬走了吗
I guess so.
看来是的
[SIGHS]
Seventeen years of my life...
17年人生
packed up in one day.
一天就打包好了
What if I just...
如果我
don't let you go?
不让你走呢
I think...
我想
the new owners might kick us out.
新屋主会赶走我们的
You could stay in our basement.
你可以住我们家地下室
Your dad'd love that.
你爸爸会喜欢的
We could hide you in a tent,
我们可以把你藏在帐篷里
like El.
就像一一
Hey.
[NANCY SIGHS]
It's gonna be okay.
没事的
[JONATHAN SIGHS]
As a wise man once said...
就像一位智者曾说
we've got shared trauma.
我们共同经历过创伤
So what's a little more, right?
再经历点又何妨
[JONATHAN CHUCKLES]
What's a little more?
再经历点又何妨
[JONATHAN CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
[STRAINS, SIGHS]
[WEAK HIGH FREQUENCY VIBRATION]
[VIBRATION INTENSIFIES, STOPS]
[PANTING]
[MIKE] They'll come back.
会恢复的
I know they will.
我知道
Thanks.
谢谢
- You packed your walkie, right? - Yes.
-你带对讲机了吧  -嗯
Because you know that I'm gonna steal Cerebro from Dustin
因为我会偷走达斯汀的脑波机
and call you so much, you're gonna have to turn it off, right?
一个劲地呼叫你  你只能烦得关掉它
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Did you talk to your mom?
你跟你妈妈谈了吗
About Thanksgiving?
感恩节的事
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. I got the okay. I'll be there.
当然  她批准了  我会去的
And then I was thinking maybe you could come up here for Christmas.
我还想 或许你圣诞节可以来这里过
And Will, too.
威尔也是
You can come before or after Christmas,
你可以在圣诞节前后来
or whatever Mrs. Byers wants,
看拜耶斯太太的意思
but I was thinking Christmas Day could be super fun,
但我觉得圣诞节那天会很好玩
because we'd all have cool new presents to play with and, uh...
因为我们那时都有棒棒的新礼物可玩
[CHUCKLES]
Sorry, that made me sound like a seven-year-old.
抱歉  我听上去像个7岁小孩
I like presents, too.
我也喜欢礼物
Yeah, cool. Yeah.
嗯  好啊
I like... I like presents, too.
我也喜欢礼物
Cool.
好啊
Mike?
迈克
Yeah?
怎么
[SIGHS]
Remember that day...
记得那天
at the cabin, you were talking to Max?
在小屋  你对麦克斯说的话
Um...
I don't think I follow.
我不太懂
You talked about your... your feelings,
你说到了你的感情
your heart.
你的心
Oh.
Oh, yeah, that. Man, that was so long ago. Um...
是啊  那个啊  好久之前了
That was really heat of the moment stuff, and
那就是一时冲口而出
we were arguing and...
我们当时在吵架
I don't really remember...
我不记得
What did I say, exactly?
我说了什么
Mike...
迈克
[EMOTIONAL SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
I love you, too.
我也爱你
霍普
[JOYCE CLICKS TONGUE, SIGHS]
Donation box?
捐赠箱
Uh, yeah, sure.
好的
[JOYCE CLEARS THROAT]
What is that?
那是什么
Uh...
It... It's the speech Hop wrote for you and Mike.
霍普为你和迈克写的讲稿
Speech?
讲稿
Yeah. You know, the heart-to-heart.
是啊  你们的谈心
He never talked to you, did he?
他没跟你们谈  是吧
[SCOFFS]
Can I read?
我能读读吗
[HOPPER] "There's something I've been wanting
"有件事我早想跟你们谈谈了
to talk to you both about."
I know this is a difficult conversation,
我知道谈这个很困难
but I care about you both very much.
但我非常在乎你们俩
And I know that you care about each other very much.
我也知道你们很在乎彼此
And that's why it's important that
所以我们一定要
we set these boundaries moving forward,
立下这些规矩  以便今后
so we can build an environment...
建立一个良好环境
where we all feel...
让我们都能感到
comfortable...
自在
trusted...
被信任
and open...
开放
"to sharing our feelings."
可以分享我们的情绪"
Feelings.
情绪
[MURMURS]
[HOPPER] Feelings.
情绪
Jesus.
天呐
[CHUCKLES]
The truth is,
事实上
for so long, I'd forgotten what those even were.
很久以来  我都忘记那是什么了
I've been stuck in one place,
我一直困在一个地方
in a cave, you might say.
可以说困在一个洞里
A deep, dark cave.
深深的黑暗的洞
And then, I left some Eggos out in the woods,
然后  我在林子里留了些松饼
and you came into my life and...
你就走进了我的生活
for the first time in a long time,
很久以来  头一次
I started to feel things again.
我开始有感觉了
I started to feel happy.
我开始感觉快乐了
But, lately, I guess I've been feeling...
但近来  我想我觉得...
distant from you.
与你疏离了
Like you're...
就好像你
you're pulling away from me or something.
你在远离我
I miss playing board games every night,
我想念每晚跟你玩棋盘游戏
making triple-decker Eggo extravaganzas at sunrise,
日出时做三层冰冻松饼大餐
watching westerns together before we doze off.
睡觉之前  一起看电视
But I know you're getting older.
但我知道你在长大
Growing.
成长
Changing.
改变
And I guess...
我猜
if I'm being really honest,
老实说
that's what scares me.
这才是让我害怕的
I don't want things to change.
我不希望事情改变
So, I think maybe that's why I came in here,
或许  这才是我来这里的原因
to try to maybe... stop that change.
想停止那种改变
To turn back the clock.
逆转时间
To make things go back to how they were.
让一切回到从前
[HOPPER SIGHS DEEPLY]
离开霍金斯  早日归来
But I know that's naive.
但我知道那是天真
It's just...
那不是
not how life works.
人生的规律
It's moving.
人生不断向前
Always moving, whether you like it or not.
不管你喜不喜欢
And, yeah, sometimes it's painful.
有时是痛苦的
Sometimes it's sad.
有时是悲伤的
And sometimes...
有时
艾瑞卡
it's surprising.
是令人意外的
捐赠
Happy.
快乐的
So, you know what?
所以知道吗
龙与地下城
Keep on growing up, kid.
继续长大吧  孩子
Don't let me stop you.
别让我拦着你
Make mistakes, learn from 'em,
犯错  然后吸取教训
and when life hurts you, because it will,
如果生活伤害了你  因为那是肯定会的
remember the hurt.
记住那种痛苦
The hurt is good.
那是好事
It means you're out of that cave.
那意味着你走出了洞
But, please,
但求你
if you don't mind,
如果你不介意
for the sake of your poor old dad,
为了你可怜的老爸
keep the door open three inches.
门至少留三英寸
[LAUGHS]
[SNIFFLES]
[SOBS]
["HEROES" BY PETER GABRIEL PLAYING]
♪ I ♪
♪ I will be king... ♪
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Are you okay?
你还好吗
Yeah.
嗯
[SNIFFLES]
Time to go?
该走了
Yeah.
嗯
I'll be out in a minute.
我就出去
Okay.
好
♪ Oh, we could be heroes ♪
♪ Just for one day ♪
♪ Oh, we can be us ♪
♪ I ♪
♪ I can remember ♪
♪ Standing ♪
♪ Standing by the wall ♪
♪ And the guns ♪
♪ Shot above our heads ♪
♪ Oh, we can be heroes ♪
♪ Just for one day ♪
后面还有
[WIND WHISTLING]
[WIND HOWLING]
[OMINOUS SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
苏联  堪察加半岛
[IN RUSSIAN] No. Not the American.
不  不是那美国人
[LOCK CLICKING]
[IN RUSSIAN] No, I'm begging you... No! Don't!
不  我求你  不要
No! Please! No! Don't!
不要  求你 别
[PRISONER] No, don't!
别这样
Don't do this!
[PRISONER] Let me go!
放开我
[PRISONER GRUNTS] Let me go!
☆谢谢观赏☆
喜马拉雅主播 & 微信公众号:
美国青少年英语
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
[PRISONER YELLS IN RUSSIAN]
[PRISONER CONTINUES YELLING]
[PRISONER WAILS AND GRUNTS]
[PRISONER GRUNTS]
[MUTTERING IN RUSSIAN]
Don't leave me in here.
别丢下我
[MUTTERING IN RUSSIAN]
Let me out,
放我出去
I'm innocent.
我是无辜的
I'm innocent!
I'm begging you, please!
求你  求你
[METAL SQUEALING]
[DOOR HINGE SQUEALING]
[SNARLING]
[SNARLING AND GROWLING]
[DEMOGORGON SHRIEKS]
[SNARLING AND SQUEALING]
[SNARLING]
[CHITTERS]
[SQUELCHING AND CLICKING]
[SNARLING]
[SCREAMS]
[SCREECHING]
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[MONKEY SCREECHING]